Finding Aid for the Collection of Materials About Protest Movements LSC.0550
UCLA Library Special Collections
A Collection of Materials About Protest Movements
1958-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0550
14.5 Linear Feet (29 boxes and 3 oversize folders)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Fraser, 1970-74.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942328123606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of handbills, newspapers, mimeographed handouts, posters, and other miscellaneous ephemera from various protest organizations in the U.S., West Germany, Sweden, and other European countries. Includes anti-war periodicals, materials from Columbia University, G.I. underground materials, materials from Freie Universität Berlin, and the Berliner Extra.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Social movements -- Europe -- Archives.; Social movements -- Germany (West) -- Archives.; Social movements -- United States -- Archives.
- Anti-War Movement Periodicals
  - Issues & Actions. (Box 1)
  - Memo (WSP). (Box 1)
  - Vietnam Summer News. (Box 1)
  - Women's International. (Box 1)
  - League for Peace & Freedom. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous anti-war movement periodicals. (Box 1)
  - Radical Student literature. (Box 1)
- United States University Protest Movements
  - New York City University broadsides and periodicals. (Box 2)
  - New York City University protest literature. (Box 2)
  - Student Mobilization Committee (SMC). (Box 2)
  - Columbia University
    - Periodicals. (Box 2)
    - Protest literature. (Box 2)
    - Multi-page publications., (1967-1969). (Box 2)
    - Broadsides., (1969-1970). (Box 2)
    - Protest movement. (Box 3)
    - Periodicals., (1967-1968). (Box 3)
    - The Review. (Box 3)
    - Periodicals and underground newspapers., (1969-1970). (Box 3)
- G.I. Underground
  - Periodicals. (Box 3, Box 4)
  - Ephemera. (Box 4)
  - Voice of Lumpen. (Box 4)
- Radical Underground periodicals: New York, Portland. (Box 4)
- Foreign Protest Movements, Primarily German
  - German Literature., (1967-1970). (Box 4)
  - German pamphlets., (1967-1970). (Box 5)
  - Easter: Broadsides, etc., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Freïe Universität: pamphlets and broadsides., (1968-1970). (Box 5)
  - German books and pamphlets of various organizations. (Box 5)
- German Protest Movements., (1971)
  - Pamphlets. (Box 6)
  - Pamphlets and periodicals. (Box 6)
  - Pamphlets, broadsides, and posters. (Box 6)
- German and West Berlin political underground ephemera. (Box 7)
- Berliner Extra. Political underground pamphlets. (Box 8)
- West Germany. (Box 9-11, 14-16)
- Student protest--Germany. (Box 13)
- Berlin Left--Students--Frankfurt. (Box 17)
- Sweden. (Box 18)
- U.S. (Box 19)
- Frankfurt. (Box 27)
- Germany, Sweden. (Box 23, 24 and 30)
- Germany. (Box 12, 20-22, 26 and 28)
- European, U.S. (Box 25)
- Anti-war broadsides and multi-paged items. (Box 29)
- European Posters. v.p., ca., 1958-1971. (Box 31, Box 32, Box 33)
  General note
  Located in Map Room.